Sahil Ajmera

https://sahil-ajmera.github.io | sa7810@rit.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahil-ajmera-b6144092/ | https://github.com/Sahil-Ajmera | +1(646)571-9799

CAREER SUMMARY

Dedicated and versatile software engineer with one-year co-op experience in different domains handling different kinds of projects with skills in programming and building and maintaining software applications. Seeking an entry-level position as a Software Developer. Available - December 2019.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York

Expected December 2019

Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.96 / 4.0

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Foundations of Algorithms, Introduction To Big Data, Foundations of Intelligent Systems, Introduction to Computing Security, Advanced Database Systems, Information Retrieval and Text Analytics

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal, Karnataka, India

Earned 2017

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

SKILLS

Certifications: Oracle Certified Professional JAVA SE6 Programmer, Microsoft Technical Associate for Cloud Fundamentals

 $\textbf{Programming Languages:} \ Python, Java, \textit{C}\#$

Relational Database Management Systems: SQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle 11g

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, Materialize

Desktop Application Development: Qt Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Orchestration Tools: Juju Charms, Ansible Playbooks

Source Control: Git

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Lenovo Software Development Co-op – Data Center Group Morrisville, North Carolina

August 2018 - Present

- Added features to Lenovo's RHHI offering by leading efforts on instantiation, configuration and validation of platforms like CloudForms, ManageIQ and Gitlab.
- Created a desktop application for ForkLift operators that gives information about the load they are carrying and the lane they are carrying that load to. (Presented at MWC 2019)
- Created 3 Rapid Access Demos as a means of proof of technology allowing customers and partners with remote testing of Lenovo Data Center solutions.
- Technologies used Python, C#, Juju Charms, Qt, MQTT, Red Hat Satellite, RHVM, RHEL, CloudForms, ManageIQ, Ansible, Materialize, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET.

American Institutes For Research

Washington, District of Columbia

May 2018 – August 2018

Software Engineer Intern

- Integrated existing workflow of Item Card report generation into workflow of Custom Pdf report generation so that statistics of items can also be printed while making a Custom Pdf Report.
- Diagnosed bugs and implemented new features as per client requirements.
- Technologies Used: C♯, .NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, SQL, SQL Server

PROJECTS

Gender recognition: Technique using PCA and GA

January 2017 - April 2017

- Achieved a 6% accuracy improvement over traditional gender recognition technique on the FERET dataset.
- Technologies Used: Python, MATLAB, WEKA

College website for ease of submission of student details to NBA

February 2016 - April 2016

- Built a website for ease of storage of information by the college to be presented to National Board of Accreditation.
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, J2EE, MySQL

Variations of K-Means: Removing Randomness of Initial Centroids

October 2015

- Improved efficiency of K-Means by providing a resolution to the issue of random initial centroids using UCI Bank Marketing dataset.
- Technologies Used: Java